The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
Even within that brilliant history,
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
Despite being relatively unknown
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
and lacking a game record,
にもかかわらず—
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
A phantom sixth man.
幻のシックスマンがいた と
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Translation Check   AMS
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Dakara itta janai ka
Didn’t I already tell you?
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
Yowasa wo uri ni shitatte
That even if you use your weakness as a selling point.
Timing       sangofe
Mae ni nanka susume ya shinaindaze
You won’t progress at all.
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
Nee hakanai jibun
Hey, my ephemeral self.
Enshutsu shitatte dare mo mukandou
Even if I produce, nobody'll care.
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
Kodoku ga sainamu yoru ni datte
Even on nights when I’m tormented by my loneliness,
Karaokes      KmE
Asu machi wabiru hikari ga aru
there’s a light that’s impatiently waiting for tomorrow.
Tsuyogaru yowai jibun wo mitomerareru tsuyosa wo
I’m weak and just putting up a strong front, but I will start
Hajimerunda yareru mon sa
gathering the strength I need to admit that I can do it.
Soko kara mae wo mui chatte
From there, I’ll look straight ahead.
Aruke
And I’ll walk,
Hashire
I’ll run,
nando demo
no matter how many times it takes.
Choushi hazure no koe datte ii sa
Doesn’t matter if I’m out of tune.
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Sore ga doushitan datte
What’s wrong with that?
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
Encoding      Your Mom
Sakebunda ore no ban da can you do it?
Now shout, it’s my turn, can you do it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Suru to dou darou nan datte
When I do it, how’s that?
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Kowaku nanka naku natten ze
Somehow my fears are all gone.
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Kyou ga wagami da
It’s my day today...
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
I
can
do
it
You
can
do
it
We
can
do
it
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
Is this the basketball club?
（火神(かがみ)）バスケ部ってここか？
I'm Kuroko.
（黒子(くろこ)）黒子はボクです
（日向(ひゅうが)）うわぁ 何？
いつからいたの？
What? How long have you been there?
I'm not looking to play basketball for fun.
（火神）オレが求めてんのは
お遊びのバスケじゃねえ
I want to play a more serious game that really gets me going.
もっと全力で 血が沸騰するような
勝負がしてえんだ
He's the invisible regular of Teiko who excelled at passing.
（リコ）
元 帝光中のレギュラーで—
パス回しに特化した
見えない選手…
The phantom sixth member of the Generation of Miracles!
“キセキの世代”
幻のシックスマン…！
That's why I hate the weak!
（火神）だから 弱(よえ)えヤツは
ムカつくんだよ！
You have to make the shot, dumbass!
ちゃんと決めろ タコ
Just how strong is the Generation of Miracles?
（火神）“キセキの世代”ってのは
どんくらい 強(つえ)えんだ
If I played them now, how would I do?
オレが今 やったらどうなる？
You'd be destroyed instantly.
（黒子）瞬殺されます
ただでさえ
天才の５人が今年—
The five prodigies have each gone on
to play for their own schools.
それぞれ違う強豪校に
進学しました
I've decided.
（火神）決めた そいつら全員
ぶっ倒して 日本一になってやる
I'll crush all of them and become the best player in Japan.
I've also decided.
ボクも決めました
I will be the shadow to your light
君という光の影として—
and make you the best player in Japan.
ボクも君を日本一にする
（火神）ハハッ やっべえ
Oh, man. I'm so excited I can't sit still.
ウズウズして
ジッとしてらんねえ
I don't care if it's not an official game.
（火神）公式戦じゃなくても
何でもいいから 早くやりてえ！
I just wanna play them!
Episode 2
I'm Serious
A game?
（日向）試合？
オマエ まだ 出れないよ
You can't play yet.
W-Why?
はっ？ なんで？
What is this, Captain?
なっ 何ですか キャプテン
オレの何がダメなんすか！？
How am I not good enough?
（日向）あ〜 じゃなくて
オマエ まだ仮入部だろ？
You're still a trial member.
You're not an official member yet.
正式な部員じゃねえもん
Huh?
I knew you had potential.
（リコ）よ〜し こいつは伸びると
思ってたのよぉ〜
育てるって ホントいいわぁ〜
Nothing beats cultivating talent.
Coach!
（火神）カントク！！
（リコ）ぶ〜っ！！
Coach, give me an official club membership form.
カントク 本入部届 くれ
What is it with today?
（リコ）何なの も〜 今日は〜
You too?
あんたも？
Too?
I'd like an official club membership form.
（黒子）本入部届ください
That bastard.
あいつ…
Just how impatient are you rascals?
まったく２人そろって
どんだけ せっかちよ
このワンパク坊やめ
What'd you call me?
（火神）何だ それ？
Well, you both have potential,
まあ即戦力だし ベンチに
空きあるから 大歓迎よ
and we've got room on the bench,
so we'd be happy to have you.
Now I can play in a game, right?
よーし これで試合に
出れんだな
Hold it right there.
（リコ）あー ちょい待ち
（火神）あ？
ただし受け付けるのは
月曜 ８時40分の屋上ね
I'll only accept your form on Monday at 8:40 on the roof.
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
Boys' Basketball Club
The Fighting Freshmen
Kanto Tournament Appearance!!
Seirin Student Newspaper
He wasn't kidding.
やっぱ それなりなんだな
Yes, they're strong.
（黒子）ええ 強いですよ
わっ！ テメエは普通に現れろ！
意表をつくな！！
Why can't you show up normally?!
Stop coming out of nowhere!
Library
（火神）ぐっ…
おちょくってんのか
Are you making fun of me?
You're making fun of me, aren't you?!
おちょくってんだよな？
オイコラ！
No.
（黒子）違います
（火神）くっ…！
Library
痛い…
That hurt.
I don't believe it.
（火神）マジ 信じらんねえ
How could anyone call
普段は影 薄いだけの
こいつが バスケじゃ—
an invisible guy like him the phantom sixth member?
幻のシックスマンなんて
呼ばれてるなんて
How did that happen anyway?
そういや なんでだ？
他の“キセキの世代”は—
The rest of the Generation of Miracles all went on to play for strong schools.
みんなもっと
強豪に行ったんだよな
Why didn't he go with them?
なんで こいつは
行かなかったんだ？
んん… おい 黒子…
Hey, Kuroko.
（景虎(かげとら)）今年もやる？
You're doing it again this year?
In order to reach their full potential with all those eyes on them,
衆人環視の中で
最大限の力を 発揮するには—
they've got to at least show that much courage.
あれくらいの度胸は
見せてもらわないと
Are you sure it wasn't a ploy to get you?
（景虎）そらあ オマエを乗せる
方便だったんじゃないのか？
今年も乗せてほしいの
I want them to get me again this year.
（景虎）乱暴だなあ
You're so reckless.
I'm glad you're passionate, but it's not good for your skin.
熱心なのはいいが お肌に悪いぞ
You should get some rest.
もう休め
Just a little longer.
（リコ）もうちょっと！
２年の個別プログラムを
詰めとかないと
I still need to finish the second years' individual programs.
たいがいにな
Don't push yourself too hard.
育てるって いいわあ
Nothing beats cultivating talent.
フッフッフ 待っていたぞ
I've been waiting for you.
アホなのか？
Are you stupid?
決闘？
Is this a duel?
I forgot all about it, but on Mondays...
つーか 忘れてたけど 月曜って…
The morning assembly is in five minutes!
あと５分で 朝礼じゃねーか！！
（エコー）
Hurry up and take it.
（火神）
ほら！ とっとと受け取れよ
（リコ）その前に１つ
言っておくことがあるわ
Before that, I have something to tell you.
I made a promise when the captain asked me to be his coach last year.
去年 あいつらにカントク
頼まれたとき 約束したの
I promised to focus solely on pushing the team towards the national championship.
全国目指して
ガチでバスケをやること
If you don't think you're ready for that,
もし あんたたちに
その覚悟がなければ—
同好会もあるから
そちらへどうぞ
there are other clubs better suited to you.
What? Of course I'm—
はあ？ そんなん
あるに決まってんだ…
I know you're strong,
（リコ）あんたらが
強いのは知ってるわ
けど それより
大切なことを確認したいの
but I need to know you have something even more important.
No matter how hard you practice,
どんだけ練習を
真面目にやっても—
“いつか”だの
“できれば”だのじゃ—
"someday" and "maybe" aren't good enough.
いつまでも弱小だからね
I need to know you have ambitious goals and the will to accomplish them.
具体的 かつ 高い目標と—
それを必ず達成しようとする
意志が欲しいの
んで 今！
学年 クラス 名前—
Give me your year, class, and name.
Announce your goals here and now.
今年の目標を
ここから宣言してもらいます！
If you fail to achieve them, you'll come back up here,
さらに できなかったときは
ここから—
strip naked, and confess your feelings for the girl you love.
全裸で好きな子に
コクってもらいます
All the second years did it last year.
今いる２年は 全員
去年やったのよ
What? No one told me about this.
（降旗(ふりはた)）はぁ？ 聞いてね〜
I heard about it when they recruited me.
（福田(ふくだ)）
いや… 勧誘のとき 言ってた
But I didn't think they'd actually...
（河原(かわはら)）けど まさかここまで…
Like I said before,
さっきも言ったけど 具体的で
相当な高さのハードルでね！
I'm looking for something concrete and reasonably ambitious.
You'll have to do better than
"play my first game" or "do my best."
“１回戦突破”とか
“頑張る”とかは やり直し
This'll be easy.
余裕じゃねえか
This isn't even a test.
（火神）テストにもなんねえ
（リコ）えっ！？
Class 1-B, number 5, Kagami Taiga!
１ーＢ ５番！ 火神大我(たいが)！！
I will defeat the Generation of Miracles
“キセキの世代”を倒して—
and become the best player in Japan!
日本一になる！
（エコー）
（日向）
うわあ 今年もやんのかよ…
Is she doing that again this year?
（小金井(こがねい)）うわ…
（火神）っと
Who's next?
（リコ）次は？
（３人）うっ…
If you don't hurry up, the teachers will get here.
（リコ）早くしないと
先生 来ちゃうよ〜
（降旗）あの〜
（リコ）ん！
Excuse me.
Could I say I want a girlfriend?
彼女 欲しいとかじゃ
ダメですかね？
Nope.
却下！ 他には？
What else do you have?
I-I've got one.
じ… じゃあ 僕が
Okay.
おし！ 行け〜
You can do it.
Class 1-A, Kawahara Koichi, from Chuo Ward, Tokyo!
１ーＡ 河原浩一(こういち)！
東京都中央(ちゅうおう)区出身！
I was a sickly kid, so I couldn't play sports!
子供の頃は 病弱で スポーツ
どころじゃありませんでした！
Things started to change for me in kindergarten...
それが変わってきたのは
幼稚園の…
I'll never forget the all-star game I saw at school in fifth grade!
小学５年のときには
林間学校へ行って—
みんなと観たオールスターの
中継が 忘れられません
It was the first time I ever thought basketball was cool...
あのとき 自分は—
初めて バスケットを
かっこいいなと思いました
I joined my school's basketball club in middle school,
中学でバスケ部に入ったときは
まともにプレーできず—
but I wasn't very good.
I was always dragging my team down, and I was miserable.
足 引っ張ってばかりで
ひたすら自分が惨めでした
But...
でも…
次！！
Next!
Um, I want a girlfriend.
（降旗）あの オレ
彼女が欲しいんですけど
I said no already!
却下だっつうの
Class 1-D, Fukuda Hiroshi!
１ーＤ 福田 寛(ひろし)！
I like helping others,
自分は人のために
なることが好きなので—
so when I heard an upperclassman asking for help,
先輩が 助っ人募集と言うのを聞き
迷うことなく入部を決めました！
I immediately offered my assistance!
Who knew he'd take my joke seriously?
（伊月）オレのダジャレを
真に受けるとはな
He must not have understood it.
（小金井）ってことは シャレが
通じてねえってことだよな
Class 1-D, Furihata Koki.
１ーＤ 降旗光樹(こうき)！
The girl I like said she'd go out with me if I became the best at something!
好きな子が オレが何かで
一番になったら—
付き合ってくれてもいいって
言ってる
I joined the basketball team to become number one!
だからオレは バスケで
一番になろうと思う！
Doing this really helped us focus last year.
（日向）去年あれやったおかげで
みんな シャキッとしたからなあ
This could be a good tradition.
伝統にすんのも アリかもな
これでダメならオレ
入部できなくて いいっス
If that's not good enough,
I don't mind if I can't join the team.
ある意味 感動した
I guess I'm moved.
（リコ）次は？
（黒子）すいません
Who's next?
Excuse me.
I'm not good at speaking loudly, so could I use this?
ボク 声 張るの苦手なんで
コレ使ってもいいですか？
Where did you get that?
どこから…
（教師）コラー！！
Hey!
The basketball club again?!
（教師）またかバスケ部！
（リコたち）うわ！
Crap, we were almost finished.
くっそぉ！
もうちょっとだったのに…
（教師）去年 散々 注意したよな
もうやらないって言わなかったか？
I warned you last year.
Didn't you say you'd never do this again?
You should know what's right and wrong at your age!
だいたいな １年！
オマエらはな…
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Thank you very much.
（店員）ありがとうございましたー
ちっ ちょっと大声
出したくらいで あんな怒るかよ
I can't believe he got so mad over a little shouting.
I didn't even finish, and I got in trouble too.
未遂だったのに
ボクも怒られました
You again?
またいるのかよ！
つーか店 変えようかな…
Maybe I should start going somewhere else.
We aren't allowed on the roof anymore.
（黒子）屋上 入れなく
なっちゃったみたいですけど—
What will we do if we can't join the basketball team?
入部できなかったら
どうしましょう
ふんっ それはねえだろ
That's not gonna happen.
We'll see.
（黒子）そうでしょうか
（火神）ん？
ああ ところでオマエさ—
By the way, why didn't you go to some big name school like the other five guys?
なんで他の５人みてえに
名の知れた強豪校に行かねえんだ？
そもそも幻のシックスマンなんて
言われてるくらいじゃねえか
You were good enough to be known as the phantom sixth man.
Is there some reason you play basketball?
オマエがバスケやるのには
何か理由があるんじゃねえの？
My middle school's basketball team had one core principle:
ボクがいた中学のバスケ部には
唯一無二の基本理念がありました
"Winning is everything."
それは 勝つことがすべて
Instead of teamwork, we pushed the
そのために必要だったのは
チームワークなどではなく—
individual talents of the Generation of Miracles to win.
ただ“キセキの世代”が—
圧倒的個人技を
行使するだけのバスケット
Nothing could beat us, but we weren't a team.
それが最強だった
けど もはやそこに
チームはなかった
The five of them approved,
５人は肯定してたけど
ボクは 何か—
but I felt we lacked something important.
大切なものが
欠落してる気がしたんです
So, what?
で 何だよ？
オマエのバスケで—
Are you gonna beat the Generation of Miracles your own way?
“キセキの世代 倒し”でも
すんのか？
そう思ってたんですけど
That's what I was thinking.
マジかよ！
Seriously?
Your words and the coach's words really struck me.
（黒子）それよりボクは
この学校で—
君と カントクの言葉にしびれた
Now my biggest reason to play is to try and make you and our team the best in Japan.
今 ボクがやる
一番の理由は—
君とこのチームを
日本一にしたいからです
We're not gonna try.
（火神）“したい”じゃねえよ
We're gonna be the best.
日本一にすんだよ！
あん？ 何の騒ぎだ？
What's all the commotion?
WE WILL BE THE BEST IN JAPAN
This could be interesting enough to work.
面白いから これもアリかな
Basketball Club
Huh? Is this...
ん？ あれ
Basketball
Magazine
Monthly
Basketball
Magazine
Monthly
Basketball
Magazine
Monthly
Basketball
Magazine
Monthly
Basketball
Magazine
Monthly
Didn't this issue come out when Kuroko was at Teiko?
これって黒子が
帝光にいた頃のじゃん？
お〜 １人１人
特集 組まれてるよ
All the players are featured.
黒子は…
Kuroko...
...doesn't have an article.
記事 ねえな
Even though he was the sixth man.
シックスマンなのに
取材 来なかったの？
Didn't they come to interview you?
They did, but ended up forgetting about me.
来たけど 忘れられました
So sad.
（３人）せつねえ〜！！
Besides, I'm nothing like the other five.
そもそも ボクなんかと
５人は全然 違います
They're true prodigies.
あの５人は本物の天才ですから
She's back!
戻りました！
カントク 戻りました！
The coach is back!
We're gonna play a practice game.
練習試合
オッケーだったみたいっス
I wonder who we're playing?
どこと組んだんだろうなあ
Who knows?
（福田）さあ… でもなんか
スキップしてましたけど
She was skipping for some reason though.
なっ！ スキップしてた！？
She was skipping?!
Be ready, everyone.
オイ… 全員 覚悟しとけ
あいつが
スキップしてるってことは—
If she's skipping,
our next opponent's gonna be really tough.
次の試合相手 相当ヤベえぞ
Seirin Private High School
This is Seirin?
（男）あ〜 ここか誠凛(せいりん)
さすが新設校
New and pristine, just like I expected.
キレイっスねえ
Isn't he hot?
（女子生徒１）見て！
あの人 カッコよくない？
And tall. Wait, is he...
（女子生徒２）背も高っ…！
ってもしかして あの人—
The model!
モデルの…！
（女子生徒３）カッコい〜
Not yet!
（伊月）いや まだだ
（火神）ぐおおお
（降旗）速っ…！
He's so quick!
おりゃっ
（福田）うおお！
（河原）ナイッシュー！
Nice!
He's amazing.
すげーな フルスピードから
あの切り返し
Such a quick turn at full speed!
He's no ordinary human.
キレが おんなじ人間とは思えね〜
（土田(つちだ)）もしかしたら
“キセキの世代”にも—
He might even beat the Generation of Miracles.
勝ってるかもな
He might really be able to beat them with that.
今のならマジで“キセキの世代”
倒せんじゃねえ？
あんな動き
そうそうできねえって
That's not an easy maneuver.
Maybe he's better than them already.
むしろ もう超えてるかも！
From what I've seen, you wouldn't even reach their feet.
今の完成度では
彼らの足元にも及ばない
That's what I said, but...
とは言ったけど… ん…
Gather round, everyone!
（リコ）よし！ 全員集合！
（部員たち）はい！！
Yes, ma'am!
海常(かいじょう)高校と練習試合！？
A practice game against Kaijo High School?!
That's right.
そう！ 相手にとって不足なし
They won't disappoint us.
We'll put plenty of first years on the court.
１年生もガンガン使ってくよ
Disappoint us? They're way better than us.
不足どころか
すげえ格上じゃねえか…
Are they really that good?
（河原）そんなに強いんですか？
They're strong at the national level.
（日向）全国クラスの強豪校だよ
They play in the Inter-High every year.
インターハイとか
毎年フツーに出てる
And this year, Kaijo got their hands on one of the Generation of Miracles, Kise Ryota.
そして海常は今年
“キセキの世代”の１人—
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)を獲得したとこよ
（降旗）えっ！？
（福田）あの—
Him?
The Generation of Miracles?
“キセキの世代”が？
（火神）まさか
こんなに早く やれるなんてな
I never thought I'd get to play them so soon.
What a blessing.
ありがてえ！
テンション上がるぜ！
I'm getting excited.
Apparently, Kise works as a model.
しかも 黄瀬って
モデルやってるらしいぞ
Seriously? Amazing.
マジ！？ すげえ！
Good looking and good at basketball? That's brutal.
カッコよくてバスケうまいとか
ひどくね〜？
Idiot.
アホ
なっ… え！？ 何？
Huh? What?
What are all these people doing here?
なんで こんなに
ギャラリーできてんの？
Uh, I didn't mean for this to happen.
（男）あ〜もう こんなつもりじゃ
なかったんスけど
That's...
あいつは…
（リコ）なんでここに
“キセキの世代”—
What is the Generation of Miracles' Kise Ryota
doing here?
黄瀬涼太が…？
（黒子）あ… お久しぶりです
It's good to see you again.
（黄瀬）久しぶり
Good to see you.
Kise Ryota.
黄瀬涼太…
Sorry, really. Um...
スイマセン マジで
あの〜 えっと ていうか—
Do you think you could wait five minutes?
５分 待っててもらっていいスか？
There.
（黄瀬）よっと
W-What are you doing here?
な なんでここに？
When I heard our next opponent was Seirin,
（黄瀬）いや〜 次の相手
誠凛って聞いて—
I remembered Kurokocchi went here,
黒子っちが 入ったのを
思い出したんで—
so I thought I'd come say hi.
あいさつに来たんっスよ
We were best friends in middle school.
中学のとき
一番 仲良かったしね
Not any more than anyone else.
普通でしたけど
ヒドッ！ あああ〜
You're so mean!
Kise Ryota.
（降旗）“黄瀬涼太”
Though he only started basketball in his second year of middle school,
“中学２年からバスケを始めるも
恵まれた体格とセンスで—”
his exceptional physical abilities and instincts got him on the Teiko team as a regular in a heartbeat.
“瞬く間に強豪 帝光で
レギュラー入り”
Continually Improving
All-Rounder
Kise Ryota
While he has less experience
than the other four,
“他の４人と比べると
経験値の浅さはあるが—”
“急成長を続ける
オールラウンダー”
he's a rapidly improving all-arounder.
Since your second year?
（日向）中２から！？
That article exaggerated quite a bit.
（黄瀬）いや〜 あの
大げさなんスよ その記事 ホント
I'm glad to be called part of the Generation of Miracles,
“キセキの世代”なんて
呼ばれるのはうれしいけど—
but I'm the worst of the bunch.
その中でオレは
一番 下っ端ってだけですわ
They bullied me and Kurokocchi for it all the time.
だから黒子っちとオレは
よく イビられたよなあ？
ボクは別になかったです
That never happened to me.
What? It was just me?
あれ？ オレだけ〜？ なっ！？
Ow! What was that for?
った〜 ちょ… 何？
Kagami!
（日向）火神！
（リコ）火神君！
Sorry for interrupting your little reunion,
（火神）
せっかくの再会中 ワリィな
but don't tell me you came all the way here just to greet us.
けど わざわざ来て
あいさつだけも ねえだろ
ちょっと相手してくれよ
イケメン君
Why don't you play with me a little, pretty boy?
What? I don't know if I'm ready.
え〜 そんな
急に言われても〜
あ〜でも さっき…
But I just...
ふうん
Fine, let's do it.
よし やろっか！
いいもん 見せてくれたお礼
I have to thank you for that display.
ったく もう〜
Unbelievable.
This could be bad.
（黒子）マズイかもしれません
（リコ）え？
Huh?
（火神）ちっ！ どあっ！
He learns plays as soon as he sees them and makes them his own.
（黒子）彼は 見たプレーを
一瞬で自分のものにする
This isn't simple imitation.
（リコ）しかもこれって
模倣とか そんなレベルじゃない
This is ridiculous! I just did that, but...
（火神）ざけんな！ それさっき
オレが… なのに… ウソだろ…！
You've gotta be kidding!
（火神）ぐっ！
（降旗）うわ 火神もすげえ！
Kagami's on fire too.
（火神）オレよりキレてて…
しかも パワーも…！
He's quicker than me. Stronger, too.
This is the Generation of Miracles.
これが“キセキの世代”…
黒子 オマエの友達
すごすぎねえ？
Kuroko, your friend's way too good.
I don't know that person.
（黒子）あんな人 知りません
（河原）え？
Huh?
To be honest,
正直さっきまで ボクも
甘いことを考えていました
I may have underestimated him until just now.
It's only been a few months since I left them,
でも 数か月
会ってないだけなのに—
but the Generation of Miracles has
予想を超える速さで
“キセキの世代”は進化してる
improved far more quickly than I expected.
ん〜 これは ちょっとなあ〜
I don't know about this.
（黄瀬）こんな拍子抜けじゃ—
After something so disappointing, I can't just leave now.
やっぱ あいさつだけじゃ
帰れないっスわ
Give us Kurokocchi.
やっぱ 黒子っち ください
Come join us.
ウチにおいでよ
また一緒に バスケやろ
Let's play basketball together again.
I seriously respect you, Kurokocchi.
マジな話 黒子っちのことは
尊敬してるんスよ
It's a waste of your talents to stay here.
こんなとこじゃ
宝の持ち腐れだって ね？
What do you say?
どうスか？
I am honored to hear you say that.
そんなふうに
言ってもらえるのは光栄です
I must respectfully decline your offer.
丁重にお断りさせていただきます
That doesn't make any sense.
（黄瀬）文脈おかしくねえ〜！？
Besides, this isn't like you.
そもそも らしくねえっスよ
勝つことがすべてだったじゃん
Winning was everything.
なんで もっと強いとこ
行かないんスか？
Why didn't you go somewhere better?
My thinking has changed since then.
あのときから考えが変わったんです
More importantly, I made a promise to Kagami.
何より 火神君と約束しました
I told him we'd beat you, the Generation of Miracles.
君たちを
“キセキの世代”を倒すと
It really isn't like you to joke around like that.
やっぱ らしくねえっスよ
そんな冗談 言うなんて
This is the Generation of Miracles.
（火神）これが“キセキの世代”
スゲエわ マジ
They really are amazing!
And there's four more guys stronger than him.
しかも もっと強(つえ)えのが
まだ ４人もいんのかよ
I can't help but smile.
ニヤけちまう
What are you doing?
ったく何だよ
オレのセリフとんなよ 黒子
I was gonna say that, Kuroko.
I still have no sense of humor.
冗談 苦手なのは
変わってません 本気です
I'm serious.
だって悔しくて まじ情けなくて
datte kuyashikute maji nasakenakute
It's frustrating, it's really shameful.
止まらない涙を笑いたきゃ笑え
tomaranai namida wo waraitakya warae
If you want to laugh at my unstoppable tears, go ahead and laugh.
不公平すぎだろ 生まれつき違うんだ
fukouheisugi daro umaretsuki chigaunda
Isn't it too unfair? We're different the moment we're born.
遠くなる背中を指くわえて見てる
tooku naru senaka wo yubi kuwaete miteru
I can only look enviously at your back getting further away.
「天才なんだよ」追いつけやしない
"tensai nanda yo" oitsuke ya shinai
"You're a genius", there's no way I can catch up.
自分の限界値を勝手に決めてた
jibun no genkaichi wo katte ni kimeteta
I willfully set my limits on myself.
本当は知ってる 本当のことを
hontou wa shitteru hontou no koto wo
I really know it, I know the truth.
誰より努力してる姿
dare yori doryoku shiteru sugata
I know I worked harder than anyone else.
見えないふりしてんのは
mienai furi shiten no wa
I'm just pretending to not see it.
わかってるんだ わかってるんだ だけど
wakatterunda wakatterunda dakedo
I know it, I know it, but...
どうにもこうにもなんないからとか
dou ni mo kou ni mo nannai kara to ka
I say it won't work or be like this and
なんとかかんとか言って
nantoka kantoka yutte
so and so and so on.
みんなも自分も自分も自分も
minna mo jibun mo jibun mo jibun mo
Fooling everyone and myself and myself
上手にだまくらかして
jouzu ni damakurakashite
and myself skillfully.
一体全体僕は何を誇れるだろう
ittaizentai boku wa nani wo hokoreru darou
What in the world can I be proud of?
あの日のボクは僕を嗤うかな
ano hi no boku wa boku wo warau ka na
Will that me someday laugh at the me right now?
もっと もっと 空は碧いはずさ
motto motto sora wa aoi hazu sa
The sky is supposed to be much much bluer.
Now, start it right away!!
Next Episode
Kise Ryota's a monster.
（リコ）
バケモノだわ 黄瀬涼太
I'll kick the crap out of the Generation of Miracles.
（日向）なあに 蹴散らしてやるぜ
“キセキの世代”！
（リコ）ああ！ いきなり
クラッチタイム！？
Crunch time already?
You can do it, Kagami!
（日向）行け〜 火神！
Shouldn't it be you?!
Episode 3
It's Better If I Can't Win
（リコ）
って アンタじゃないんかい！